<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: magazine | 廣川政樹ポートフォリオ - Dolice Log]]></title>
  <link href="https://log.dolice.net/blog/categories/magazine/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://log.dolice.net/"/>
  <updated>2021-11-23T15:19:15+09:00</updated>
  <id>https://log.dolice.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Masaki Hirokawa]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[info@dolice.net]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[雑誌 365 Art+ Magazine 第7号にグラフィックを掲載いただきました]]></title>
    <link href="https://log.dolice.net/blog/2021/11/23/magazine-365-art-plus-magazine-case7/"/>
    <updated>2021-11-23T14:59:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>https://log.dolice.net/blog/2021/11/23/magazine-365-art-plus-magazine-case7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/magazine/365_art_plus_magazine/case7/dolice_case7_integrated2.jpg" title="365 Art+ Magazine 第7号「365 Art+ Case 7. Perfection」" alt="365 Art+ Magazine 第7号「365 Art+ Case 7. Perfection」" /></p>

<p>雑誌 365 Art+ Magazine 第7号「<a href="https://365artshop.stores.jp/items/616ed9f51bfe1918eef267fb" title="365 Art+ Case 7. Perfection">365 Art+ Case 7. Perfection</a>」にグラフィック「<a href="https://dolice.design/crimson" title="Crimson / 薔薇苑">Crimson / 薔薇苑</a>」を掲載いただきました（<em>本扉</em>）。</p>

<p>この作品はグラフィック制作を10年ぶりに始めて間もない頃、故郷の富山に帰省し、自然の空気をたっぷり吸収した後、東京へ戻りすぐに制作しました。</p>

<p>それ故、表現力や技術力に拙いところが多々見受けられますが、この作品には視覚表現の喜びと生命力が満ち満ちています。</p>

<p>あれから2年間、コロナの影響で富山には帰省できておらず、現在は遠くの宮崎に移り住みました。外で友人と飲んだのもあの時が最後で、もう長らく友人と会えておりません。</p>

<p>昨年の2月に東京がコロナ禍に入って以降、心境の変化があり視覚的に綺麗なだけのものは作れなくなりました。ラフの過程で形になっても GOサインが下りなくなったのです。メッセージ性の併せ持つ作品しか制作できなくなり、作品のトーンは暗く冷たい方向へシフトして行ったように思います。</p>

<p>恥ずかしながら故郷の空気が恋しく、昨年の梅雨の時点で既に限界を感じながらも、一つ一つの作品を一心不乱に仕上げて来ました。最終調整の段階では毎度吐き気を催し、色に酔い、色を判別できなくなり、やがて見えるのは光だけでした。自分の作っているものが美しいのか醜いのかすら分からなくなっていました。</p>

<p>誰に頼まれた訳でもない苦しい作業の過程で、おそらく自らの人生の課題の一つである感覚と論理の統合はある程度体得できた気がします。ただその先に、そんな人間の理屈など軽く覆してしまう、人知の及ばない世界が在ることを知りました。</p>

<p>宮崎に移り住んでから自身の未熟さを痛感し、如何にこれまで人として驕り高ぶっていたかを知りました。生身の人間として生きることの重さ、与えられた命の、生かされて来た命の尊さを知りました。自分は決して一人ではなかったのです。</p>

<p>この自らを押し潰す現実の中で、真っ暗な泥沼を無様に這いずり回るような日々の中において、自らが会得したことを如何に今後の作品に表現して行くか、これらの経験が如何に今後の作品に反映されて行くのか、この二つの目でしっかり見て行く義務があります。</p>

<p>自分が人間として正しいとは到底思えません。罪を背負っていないとはとても言い切れません。自らの持てる限りの力を振り絞っても尚、失敗や後悔ばかりです。それでも前だけを見据え、ただ愚鈍に突き進むしかありません。</p>

<p>今を境にもう一度グラフィックデザインに回帰し、美しいものを作りたい。美しいとは何なのか、何度も自分の心に問い続けて行きたい。そして、これから生まれて来る新しい命に、このちっぽけな父の、ただ精一杯の背中を見ていて欲しい。やがて本当に美しく尊く誇れるものを、その目いっぱいに広げて見せてあげたい。今はそう思っています。</p>

<p>言葉の壁も国境もないグローバル誌という貴重な媒体で、この有り難い機会を下さった編集社の方々に、心より御礼申し上げます。</p>

<p>Magazine 365 Art+ Magazine issue 7 "<a href="https://365artshop.stores.jp/items/616ed9f51bfe1918eef267fb" title="365 Art+ Case 7. Perfection">365 Art+ Case 7. Perfection</a>" published my graphic "<a href="https://dolice.design/crimson" title="Crimson">Crimson</a>" (<em>Title page</em>).</p>

<p>This work was created soon after I returned to Tokyo after returning to my hometown Toyama and absorbing a lot of natural air, shortly after I started making graphics for the first time in 10 years.</p>

<p>Therefore, there are many areas where I am not good at expression and technique, but this work is filled with the joy and vitality of visual expression.</p>

<p>In the two years since then, I have not been able to return to Toyama due to Corona, and have now moved to Miyazaki, far away. That was the last time I went out for drinks with friends, and I haven't seen them for a long time.</p>

<p>Since Tokyo was hit by the Corona disaster in February last year, I have had a change of heart and can no longer create something that is just visually beautiful. I can no longer make something that is only visually pleasing, and even if it takes shape in the rough process, I can no longer give it the go-ahead. I was only able to create works with a message, and the tone of my works shifted to a dark and cold direction.</p>

<p>I am ashamed to say that I missed the air of my hometown, and even though I felt I was already at the end of my rope during the rainy season last year, I worked tirelessly on each piece. In the final adjustment stage, I felt nauseous every time, intoxicated with colors, unable to distinguish colors, and eventually all I could see was light. I couldn't even tell if what I was making was beautiful or ugly.</p>

<p>In the process of this painful work, which I was not asked to do by anyone, I think I was able to acquire a certain degree of integration of senses and logic, which is probably one of the challenges of my life. However, beyond that, I learned that there is a world beyond human comprehension, where human logic can be lightly overturned.</p>

<p>Since moving to Miyazaki, I have become acutely aware of my own immaturity, and I have learned how proud I have been of myself as a human being. I learned the weight of living as a real human being, and the preciousness of the life we have been given and the life we have been allowed to live. I was never alone.</p>

<p>In the midst of this crushing reality, in the midst of the days of crawling around in the dark mire, I have a duty to see how I can express what I have learned in my future works, and how these experiences will be reflected in my future works.</p>

<p>I don't believe that I am righteous as a human being. I can't say that I don't have sins on my shoulders. Even though I have done everything in my power, I still have failures and regrets. Even so, I have no choice but to look forward to the future and push forward foolishly.</p>

<p>I want to return to graphic design and create something beautiful. I want to keep asking myself over and over again what beauty is. I also want my newborn baby to be able to see the back of its tiny father doing his best. In the end, I want to show her something truly beautiful and precious that she can be proud of. That's what I'm thinking now.</p>

<p>I would like to express my heartfelt gratitude to the editorial staff of the magazine for giving me this precious opportunity to work for a global magazine that has no language barriers or borders.</p>

<h2>公式ストア・公式サイト</h2>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="https://365artshop.stores.jp/items/616ed9f51bfe1918eef267fb" title="365 Art+ Case 7. Perfection">365 Art+ Case 7. Perfection</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://365artshop.stores.jp" title="365 Art+ Magazine">365 Art+ Magazine</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://365artplus.com" title="毎日アートマガジン">毎日アートマガジン</a></p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[雑誌 365 Art+ Magazine 第6号にグラフィックを掲載いただきました]]></title>
    <link href="https://log.dolice.net/blog/2021/11/01/magazine-365-art-plus-magazine-case6/"/>
    <updated>2021-11-01T10:17:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>https://log.dolice.net/blog/2021/11/01/magazine-365-art-plus-magazine-case6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/magazine/365_art_plus_magazine/case6/dolice_case6_cover_intergrated.jpg" title="365 Art+ Magazine 第6号「365 Art+ Case 6. DREAM」" alt="365 Art+ Magazine 第6号「365 Art+ Case 6. DREAM」" /></p>

<p>雑誌 365 Art+ Magazine 第6号「<a href="https://365artshop.stores.jp/items/6154296251244e07f1638ef4" title="365 Art+ Case 6. DREAM">365 Art+ Case 6. DREAM</a>」にグラフィック「<a href="https://dolice.design/aurora" title="Aurora / 極光">Aurora / 極光</a>」を掲載いただきました（<em>奥付</em>）。</p>

<p>世界中の素晴らしいアーティストがあらゆる垣根を超えて集結した、大変異質かつ密度の濃い雑誌です。毎号1ページずつ愛情を込めて編集されているのが伝わって来ます。</p>

<p>雑誌を開けばきっと良い発見や出会いが沢山あると思いますので、是非お手に取ってご覧ください。</p>

<p>Magazine 365 Art+ Magazine issue 6 "<a href="https://365artshop.stores.jp/items/6154296251244e07f1638ef4" title="365 Art+ Case 6. DREAM">365 Art+ Case 6. DREAM</a>" published my graphic "<a href="https://dolice.design/aurora" title="Aurora">Aurora</a>" (<em>Imprint</em>).</p>

<p>365 Art+ Magazine is a very dense magazine that brings together wonderful artists from all over the world, transcending all barriers. I can feel that each issue is edited with love and care.</p>

<p>I am sure you will find many good discoveries and encounters when you open the magazine, so please pick it up and take a look.</p>

<h2>公式ストア・公式サイト</h2>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="https://365artshop.stores.jp/items/6154296251244e07f1638ef4" title="365 Art+ Case 6. DREAM">365 Art+ Case 6. DREAM</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://365artshop.stores.jp" title="365 Art+ Magazine">365 Art+ Magazine</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://365artplus.com" title="毎日アートマガジン">毎日アートマガジン</a></p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[雑誌 365 Art+ Magazine 第5号にグラフィックを掲載いただきました]]></title>
    <link href="https://log.dolice.net/blog/2021/10/02/magazine-365-art-plus-magazine-case5/"/>
    <updated>2021-10-02T11:52:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>https://log.dolice.net/blog/2021/10/02/magazine-365-art-plus-magazine-case5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/magazine/365_art_plus_magazine/case5/dolice_case5_cover1.jpg" title="365 Art+ Magazine 第5号「365 Art+ Monotone Planet. Case 5」" alt="365 Art+ Magazine 第5号「365 Art+ Monotone Planet. Case 5」" /></p>

<p>雑誌 365 Art+ Magazine 第5号「<a href="https://365artshop.stores.jp/items/612d91b98a45720abf76c850" title="365 Art+ Monotone Planet. Case 5">365 Art+ Monotone Planet. Case 5</a>」にグラフィックを掲載いただきました（<em>裏表紙</em> / <em>奥付</em>）。</p>

<p>「<a href="https://dolice.design/reclining-buddha" title="Reclining Buddha / 涅槃像">Reclining Buddha / 涅槃像</a>」を裏表紙、「<a href="https://dolice.design/gnosticism" title="Gnosticism / 知恵の実">Gnosticism / 知恵の実</a>」を奥付に掲載いただいています。</p>

<p>世界中から素晴らしい人物とアートが厳選して紹介されている、沢山の愛が詰まった一冊です。</p>

<p>素晴らしい出会いがあると思いますので、是非お手に取ってご覧ください。</p>

<p>My graphics were published in 365 Art+ Magazine issue 5 "<a href="https://365artshop.stores.jp/items/612d91b98a45720abf76c850" title="365 Art+ Monotone Planet. Case 5">365 Art+ Monotone Planet. Case 5</a>" (<em>back cover</em> and <em>back cover</em>).</p>

<p>"<a href="https://dolice.design/reclining-buddha" title="Reclining Buddha">Reclining Buddha</a>" is on the back cover and "<a href="https://dolice.design/gnosticism" title="Gnosticism">Gnosticism</a>" is on the back cover.</p>

<p>This magazine is full of love, with a great selection of people and art from around the world.</p>

<p>Please pick up a copy of the magazine and take a look, as you are sure to have a wonderful encounter.</p>

<h2>公式ストア・公式サイト</h2>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="https://365artshop.stores.jp/items/612d91b98a45720abf76c850" title="365 Art+ Monotone Planet. Case 5">365 Art+ Monotone Planet. Case 5</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://365artshop.stores.jp" title="365 Art+ Magazine">365 Art+ Magazine</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://365artplus.com" title="毎日アートマガジン">毎日アートマガジン</a></p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[雑誌 365 Art+ Magazine 第4号にグラフィックを掲載いただきました]]></title>
    <link href="https://log.dolice.net/blog/2021/09/21/magazine-365-art-plus-magazine-case4/"/>
    <updated>2021-09-21T13:14:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>https://log.dolice.net/blog/2021/09/21/magazine-365-art-plus-magazine-case4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/magazine/365_art_plus_magazine/case4/dolice_case4.jpg" title="365 Art+ Magazine 第4号「365 Art+ Inspiration. Case 4」" alt="365 Art+ Magazine 第4号「365 Art+ Inspiration. Case 4」" /></p>

<p>雑誌 365 Art+ Magazine 第4号「<a href="https://365artshop.stores.jp/items/611e46a9f604a96d04803efa" title="365 Art+ Inspiration. Case 4">365 Art+ Inspiration. Case 4</a>」にグラフィックを掲載いただきました（<em>P 30〜P 33</em> / <em>裏表紙</em>）。</p>

<p>一昨年の暮れから約10年ぶりにグラフィック制作を再開し、暫くは新鮮で楽しい気持ちで制作していました。</p>

<p>しかし昨年の2月、東京の都心でコロナ禍へ向かう世界を目の当たりにし、アート・エンターテイメントの持つ意義と、己の無力さを痛感したのを覚えています。</p>

<p>それでも立ち上がろうと決意し「<a href="https://dolice.design/bodhisattvas-of-the-earth" title="Bodhisattvas of the Earth / 地涌の手">Bodhisattvas of the Earth / 地涌の手</a>」というグラフィックを制作したのを皮切りに、おそらく神仏の目となり耳となり、そしてメッセンジャーと化すことに感謝と喜びを見出していました。</p>

<p>今年になり、人としての幸せを求めても善いのか、生きていても良いのか悩み苦しんでいた折、何故かこれまで感想をくださった方々のことが思い出され、みっともなく泣き崩れてしまいました。</p>

<p>自己満足で何の見返りも求めずひっそりと制作して参りましたが、同じ信念を持つ雑誌に出会うことができ、心から感謝しております。</p>

<p>私以外に素晴らしい人々と作品が多数掲載されていますので、是非お手に取って見ていただければ幸いです。</p>

<p>アートが人々の心に潤いを与え、一刻の安寧を齎さんことを祈っています。</p>

<p>My graphics were featured in the 4th issue of 365 Art+ Magazine "<a href="https://365artshop.stores.jp/items/611e46a9f604a96d04803efa" title="365 Art+ Inspiration. Case 4">365 Art+ Inspiration. Case 4</a>" (<em>P 30 - P 33</em> / <em>back cover</em>).</p>

<p>At the end of the year before last, I resumed graphic production for the first time in about 10 years, and for a while I was working with a fresh and joyful feeling.</p>

<p>However, in February of last year, I witnessed the world heading towards the Corona disaster in the heart of Tokyo, and I remember being painfully aware of the significance of art and entertainment, as well as my own helplessness.</p>

<p>Nevertheless, I decided to stand up and created a graphic work called "<a href="https://dolice.design/bodhisattvas-of-the-earth" title="Bodhisattvas of the Earth">Bodhisattvas of the Earth</a>", and since then, I have been grateful and happy to be the eyes, ears, and messenger of God and Buddha.</p>

<p>This year, as I was struggling with the question of whether it is good to seek happiness as a human being or to live, I somehow remembered the people who had given me feedback, and I broke down in tears.</p>

<p>I've been quietly creating graphics for my own satisfaction, seeking nothing in return, but I'm so grateful to have found a magazine that shares my beliefs.</p>

<p>I hope you will take a look at the many wonderful people and their works in the magazine.</p>

<p>I hope that the art in this magazine will enrich people's hearts and bring them a moment of peace.</p>

<h2>公式ストア・公式サイト</h2>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="https://365artshop.stores.jp/items/611e46a9f604a96d04803efa" title="365 Art+ Inspiration. Case 4">365 Art+ Inspiration. Case 4</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://365artshop.stores.jp" title="365 Art+ Magazine">365 Art+ Magazine</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://365artplus.com" title="毎日アートマガジン">毎日アートマガジン</a></p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[JaamZIN Creative magazine 特集号刊行]]></title>
    <link href="https://log.dolice.net/blog/2020/10/10/graphic-jaam-zin-creative-magazine-special-edition/"/>
    <updated>2020-10-10T07:50:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>https://log.dolice.net/blog/2020/10/10/graphic-jaam-zin-creative-magazine-special-edition</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/magazine/jaamzin_creative_magazine_special_edition_masaki_hirokawa_2.jpg" title="Masaki Hirokawa - Special edition of JaamZIN Creative magazine" alt="Masaki Hirokawa - Special edition of JaamZIN Creative magazine" /></p>

<p><a href="https://issuu.com/jaamzin/docs/masaki_hirokawa_magazine" title="JaamZIN Creative magazine 特集号">JaamZIN Creative magazine 特集号</a>を刊行いただきました。これまでに制作したグラフィックとインタビューを掲載いただいています。丁寧に編集いただき本当に有り難いです。</p>

<p><a href="https://issuu.com/jaamzin/docs/masaki_hirokawa_magazine" title="A special issue of JaamZIN Creative magazine">A special issue of JaamZIN Creative magazine</a> has been published. It features some of the graphics and interviews that I have created so far. Thank you for this very exciting opportunity.</p>

<h5>Magazine</h5>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://issuu.com/jaamzin/docs/masaki_hirokawa_magazine" title="Masaki Hirokawa - Special edition of JaamZIN Creative magazine">Masaki Hirokawa - Special edition of JaamZIN Creative magazine</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
